all right
[Music]
from this 2020 systematic review on the
effects of egg consumption on
cholesterol here are the results of more
than 50 randomized controlled trials
nearly all of which pointing the
direction of Greater LDL blood
cholesterol with greater egg intake and
that's just looking at fasting
cholesterol taken in the morning which
is how much your liver is churning out
which is like the Baseline on top of
which the effects of diet can be
assessed we live most of our lives in a
postprandial State median after meal
steak not a fasting State and this is
what eating more and more dietary
cholesterol can do to your blood
cholesterol levels immediately after
eating shooting your levels up for hours
after a meal and then what happens after
four hours lunchtime and you can whack
your arteries with another surge of
cholesterol on top of your elevated
fasting levels
of course the only reason we care about
cholesterol is because we care about
heart disease our number one killer of
men and women and you do see for example
significantly higher coronary artery
calcium scores and those who eat more
eggs which is a sign of atherosclerotic
plaque buildup in the arteries but does
this translate into a higher risk of
heart attacks and death apparently so
based on a half dozen population studies
in the U.S following tens of thousands
of people for up to 30 years each
additional half of an egg consumed per
day was significantly associated with
higher risk of developing cardiovascular
disease and dying from all causes put
together in other words living a
significantly shorter lifespan but wait
a second egg consumption commonly
correlates with unhealthy Behavior such
as inactivity smoking and eating all
sorts of other bad stuff and hey how do
we know it's not the saturated fat and
animal protein as opposed to the
cholesterol failure to consider all
these factors could lead to different
conclusions but this study
comprehensively accounted for all these
factors also the study had longer
follow-up than the majority of the
previous studies and therefore it may
provide more power to detect
associations with even single food
products such as eggs in this case and
the study found that the significant
associations of dietary cholesterol and
death were independent of the quality of
the diet meaning if you eat let's say
you know two eggs a day but the rest of
your diet is all vegetables and you know
low sodium do these eggs pretend any
higher level of cardiovascular disease
risk the effective egg and dietary
cholesterol in general remained even
after considering an otherwise
heart-healthy dietary pattern so that
significantly increased risk of death
tied to just half an egg a day persisted
even after taking an overall diet
quality into account so it's not just
like they're eating more bacon with
their eggs when we adjust for overall
diet quality and the consumption of
specific types of food like red meat or
processed meat like bacon the
association persisted we suggest that
the entire Association is not driven by
bacon or other foods eaten with eggs
considering the negative consequences of
egg consumption and dietary cholesterol
even in the setting of a heart-healthy
dietary patterns the importance of
following evidence-based dietary
recommendations such as limiting intake
of cholesterol-rich foods should not be
dismissed
but that's exactly what the 2015 dietary
guidelines advisory committee appeared
to try to do declaring cholesterol not a
nutrient of concern for over consumption
because available evidence shows no
appreciable relationship between
consumption of dietary cholesterol and
blood cholesterol consistent with the
conclusion of an American Heart
Association American College of
Cardiology report
wait what
here's a meta-analysis of literally
hundreds of studies published like 25
years ago conclusively showing that you
can decrease blood cholesterol by
decreasing dietary cholesterol intake
an interesting thing has since happened
with cholesterol research though
industry funding of studies increase
from zero to now most cholesterol
studies are bought and paid for by the
egg industry and studies funded by the
egg board tend to use specific design
characteristics to minimize the reported
negative health effects and so now
anyone limiting their reviews to studies
published in recent years when nearly
all studies were industry funded and
specifically designed to bring about
certain predetermined outcomes you can
make eggs look more favorable than if
you included more objectively designed
research the ahaacc report for example
limited their evidence review from 1998
to 2009 I mean they knew about
meta-analyzes like this one published in
1997 but didn't give it full
consideration because these studies
predated their search time frame doctor
Kim Williams was president of the
American College of Cardiology around
the time of this Saga let's hear it
straight from the horse's mouth despite
research studies over several decades
indicating that dietary cholesterol
increases serum cholesterol levels their
2013 reports stated that there was
insufficient evidence to determine
whether lowering dietary cholesterol
helps but this was based on that limited
time search people didn't understand
that but that's what the dietary
guidelines advisory committee cited
after clarification by the American
College of Cardiology of which he was
President the final official
2015-2020 dietary guidelines for
Americans that was published followed
the position of the Institute of
medicine and told people to eat as
little dietary cholesterol as possible
and here they are here are the dietary
guidelines as recommended by The
Institute of medicine individuals should
eat as little dietary cholesterol as
possible this was reiterated in in the
2020 to 2025 guidelines dietary
cholesterol consumption
should be as low as possible the
national Academy's Institute of medicine
is who determines the recommended daily
allowances and they're very explicit
that based on all the evidence not just
a sliver in time when it comes to
dietary cholesterol which is found in
all meat Dairy and eggs intake should be
as low as possible because any intake
level above zero increases LDL
cholesterol concentration in the blood
and therefore carries increased risk of
coronary heart disease our number one
killer
after conviction for false advertising
suggesting eggs were healthy which I
detailed in one of my videos the egg
industry has spent hundreds of millions
of dollars trying to convince the public
Physicians and policy makers that
dietary cholesterol and egg yolks are
harmless but in reality regular
consumption of egg yolks should be
avoided by people at risk for
cardiovascular disease which essentially
means all North Americans who expect to
live past middle age
thank you
foreign